{
    "id": "33884800ca454825b94a7940ba42f29b",
    "title": "Identify The Adverb",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He is so pigheaded you can’t reason with him.",
            "description": "Here so modifies the adjective pigheaded. Only an adverb can modify an adjective.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "pigheaded",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Sailing alone around the world was quite a pilgrimage.",
            "description": "Quite is an adverb indicating degree. It shows to what extent.",
            "answers": [
                "sailing",
                "quite",
                "privilege"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The admiral was always nonchalant in the face of danger.",
            "description": "Always is an adverb of time. It answers the question when.",
            "answers": [
                "always",
                "nonchalant",
                "of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A person’s outward appearance was formerly thought to reveal his character.",
            "description": "Formerly is an adverb of time. Most words ending in ly are adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "outward",
                "formerly",
                "reveal"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Wearing nothing but blue clothing is only one of her peculiarities.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "nothing",
                "blue",
                "only"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He was seen driving northward.",
            "description": "Words indicating place are adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "seen",
                "driving",
                "northward"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have told you this twice.",
            "description": "Twice is an adverb of frequency. It answers the question how often.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "this",
                "twice"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "That day he arrived late.",
            "description": "Here late modifies the verb arrived. Hence it is an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "arrived",
                "late"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have already spoken to him about this.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "already",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Luckily we escaped unhurt.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "luckily",
                "escaped",
                "unhurt"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My dog understands everything. He is almost human.",
            "description": "Here the adverb almost modifies the adjective human. ",
            "answers": [
                "everything",
                "almost",
                "human"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am fully prepared for the examination.",
            "description": "Here the adverb fully modifies the adjective prepared. ",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "fully",
                "prepared"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}